<resources>
    <string name="app_name">UNA</string>
    <string name="app_title">Urals Natural Attractions</string>

    <string name="back_button">Back</string>

    <string name="chertovo_gorodishche_title">Chertovo Gorodishche</string>
    <string name="chertovo_gorodishche_info">Chertovo Gorodishche, more commonly known as Devil\'s Settlement, Devil\'s Mound, or Devil\'s City, is a rock formation near Yekaterinburg in Sverdlovsk Oblast, Ural Federal District, Russia. Made from several types of rock, the formation is a tourist attraction and archaeological site.</string>

    <string name="mount_azov_title">Mount Azov</string>
    <string name="mount_azov_info">Azov (Russian: Азов) is a mountain in Central Ural, Russia. It is located 8 km from Polevskoy meat Zyuzelsky village. It\'s one of the natural monuments of Russia. According to Aleksandr Matveyev, the configuration of the rocks gives a reason to believe that the name of the mountain derives from the Tatar word azaw teš (азау теш), meaning \'molar tooth\'. In other Turkic languages the word means \'fang\', \'edge\', or \'sting\'. The archaeologist E. Bers believed that in the Iron Age it served as a sacrificial place. According to popular beliefs, a creature from local folktales called Azovka (lit. \'the Azov girl\') lives inside Mount Azov.</string>

    <string name="iremel_title">Iremel</string>
    <string name="iremel_info">Iremel (Bashkir: Ирәмәл, Russian: Иремель) is a compact mountain ridge in the Southern Ural Mountains in the republic of Bashkortostan, Russian Federation (bordering with Chelyabinsk Oblast to the north-west). The highest peak, Bolshoy Iremel (Big Iremel), or simply Iremel, stands at 1589 metres (5200 ft) high. Maly Iremel (Small Iremel), 6 kilometers north-east, stands at 1449 meters. It is the source of the River Belaya. The highest peak of the South Urals, Mount Yamantaw (1638 meters) is located 53 kilometers south-west from Bolshoy Iremel.</string>

    <string name="lake_tavatui_title">Lake Tavatui</string>
    <string name="lake_tavatui_info">Lake Tavatui, also known as Lake Tavatuy, is a freshwater lake in Sverdlovsk Oblast, Russia. Several communities surround the lake and the nearest major city is Yekaterinburg. The lake is known for its high water quality and is a popular tourist attraction. The a website operated by the Russian Federal Agency for Tourism calls it "the pearl of the Middle Urals".</string>

    <string name="lake_itkul_title">Lake Itkul</string>
    <string name="lake_itkul_info">Lake Itkul is situated in the north of the Chelyabinsk Oblast, 20 kilometers from the town of Verkhny Ufaley. Lake Itkul was declared a natural monument. The lake is surrounded by low summits of the Ural Mountains, the highest of them being Karabayka (544 m) on the southwestern shore of Lake Itkul. Here in Lake Itkul small river flows Karabayka.</string>

    <string name="chusovaya_title">Chusovaya</string>
    <string name="chusovaya_info">The Chusovaya (Russian: Чусова́я) is a river flowing in Perm Krai, Sverdlovsk Oblast and Chelyabinsk Oblast of Russia. A tributary of the Kama, which in turn is a tributary of the Volga, discharges into the Chusovskoy Cove of the Kamsky Reservoir. The river is remarkable in that it originates on the eastern slopes of the Ural Mountains in Asia, crosses the mountains, and mostly runs on their western slopes in Europe. The Chusovaya River is widely used as a source of water. In particular, its water is taken from the Volchikhinsky Reservoir, 37 square kilometres (14 sq mi), to the Verkhneisetsky Reservoir to supply the major city of Yekaterinburg. Fifteen smaller reservoirs are spread over about 150 tributaries of the river. There are numerous metal and coal mines along the Chusovaya, and the river was intensively used to deliver their production to the western Russia. However, industrial navigation nearly halted with the development of railways in the early 20th century. Chusovoy is the major remaining port on the river. The Chusovaya River is famous for its hundreds of large rocks located along the shoreline which are the major tourist attraction of the area. Some rocks posed much danger to boats, especially during the spring thaw. They are generally called boitsy (бойцы, lit. fighters). Many of them have individual names and are protected by the state as natural monuments.</string>

    <string name="kungur_ice_cave_title">Kungur Ice Cave</string>
    <string name="kungur_ice_cave_info">Kungur Ice Cave is a karst cave located in the Urals, near the town Kungur in Perm Krai, Russia, on the right bank of the Sylva River. The cave is noted for its ice formations and is a popular tourist landmark. Inside the cave there is a set of narrow stone steps called "the female tears". The name comes from a story, that a long time ago a foreign princess tripped and fell on them. After she returned home she got married. Since then, it is said that if a woman falls down on these steps she will get married soon.</string>

    <string name="kurgazak_cave_title">Kurgazak cave</string>
    <string name="kurgazak_cave_info">Kurgazak Cave (Russian: Кургазакская пещера) is a cave in the Ural Mountains, in the Ay River valley. Located in the Chelyabinsk oblast, Russia, and between the villages Mezhevoy Alexeevka is a natural monument. The first mention of the cave belongs to the second half of the 18th century, when it was described by Peter Simon Pallas academician. The cave entrance is located at an altitude of about 20 meters, 150 meters from the Ay River. Length - 530 m, depth - 16 m. The cave is formed in the Devonian strata of limestone and karst cavity represents the main-corridor-type, consisting of three large halls interconnected passageways.</string>

    <string name="orda_cave_title">Orda Cave</string>
    <string name="orda_cave_info">Orda Cave (Ординская, Ordinskaya) is a gypsum crystal cave found underneath the western Ural Mountains. The mouth is near the shore of the Kungur River just outside Orda, Perm Krai in Russia. The cave system stretches over 5.1 kilometres (3.2 mi) with around 4.8 kilometres (3.0 mi) over the overall length being under water. This makes it one of the longest underwater caves and the largest underwater gypsum cave in the world. It contains the longest siphon in the former Soviet Union (935 meters). The mineral-rich area surrounding the cave filters the water and makes it very clear. Divers have a visibility of over 50 yards (46 m) making it an ideal location for photographic expeditions. Victor Lyagushkin, a journalist and underwater photographer, led around 150 expeditions into the caves over a six-month period in 2011. The photographs taken by his team were published in the Orda Cave Awareness Project alongside stories from other divers who had visited the cave system. The diving team were also the first people to produce a spherical panorama of an underwater cave. A local myth tells of the "Lady of the Orda Cave" who is said to live in the caves. The cave has also been visited during dives by Martyn Farr, Lamar Hires, Pascal Bernabé, and Reggie Ross.</string>

    <string name="mountains_rocks"><![CDATA[Mountains & Rocks]]></string>
    <string name="water_sites">Water Sites</string>
    <string name="caves">Caves</string>
    <string name="all">All</string>
    <string name="pick_a_site_to_view_details">Pick a site to view details</string>
    <string name="show_on_map">Show on Map</string>
</resources>